Finding aid to Record Group 9. Photographs, of the YWCA of the U.S.A. records SSC.MS.00324.RG9
Sophia Smith Collection
- Slides, 2
  - Conferences and conventions, C
    - Conventions
      - 29th, 1982
        - "The YWCA of the U.S.A.: The Sum of its Parts," script and slides for use at Convention preparation meetings, Jan 1982 (Box 1056, Folder 15)
        - "Making the Difference: An Historical YWCA Commitment," script and slides for slide-audio revolving show by Elizabeth Norris at YWCA Exhibit Booth (Box 1056, Folder 16)
        - General slides taken at Convention (Box 1056, Folder 17)
        - Script and slides for presentation about 1982 Convention (Box 1056, Folder 18)
      - 30th, 1985: Script and slides of Convention Overview for use at Convention Preparation Meetings, 1984 (Box 1056, Folder 19)
      - 1994 33rd: general slides taken at Convention (Box 1057, Folder 1-3)
  - Subseries D. International Work
    - "Training Makes the Difference! Trainees at work in ten countries of the Far East": script and slides, 30 Jun 1959 (Box 1057, Folder 4-5)
    - "A YWCA Journey": script and slides of the Rockefeller-National Geographic trip to YWCAs around the world, 1963 (Box 1057, Folder 6)
    - "YWCA World Fellowship in Action in Ethiopia": script and slides, May 1966 (Box 1057, Folder 7)
    - "YWCAs in Far Places Help Early School Leavers": script and slides, Jun 1966 (Box 1057, Folder 8)
    - "YWCA Camps Around the World," script and slides, Sep 1966 (Box 1057, Folder 9)
    - "The YWCA of Guadalajara, Mexico": script only, 1967 (Box 1057, Folder 10)
    - "South American Journey": script and slides, Feb 1967 (Box 1057, Folder 11)
    - "Visiting the YWCA Family-Around the World": script and slides, Aug 1968 (Box 1057, Folder 12)
    - "A Power to Do: The World YWCA is Woven of Many Threads": script only, 1973 (Box 1057, Folder 13)
    - "A South Pacific Journey": script and slides re Mary French Rockefeller's trip to the South Pacific with her husband and National Geographic photographers, Sep 1973 (Box 1057, Folder 14)
    - "A Celebration of Women": script and slides re dedication of the YWCA Window of Thanksgiving at the Washington Cathedral, 1978 (Box 1057, Folder 15)
    - "Breaking Barriers": script and slides by World Relations, Apr 1979 (Box 1057, Folder 16)
    - Slides of YWCAs in other countries, general, 1963-87, n.d. (Box 1057, Folder 17)
    - Slides taken by Helene Mosier
      - Africa (Box 1058)
        - General, 1966-72, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 1)
        - Liberia, 1969-72, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 2-3)
      - South America, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous, 1967-69, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 5)
  - Subseries E. Program
    - Advocacy
      - General, 1976-93, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 6)
      - ERA Demonstration and March, Washington, DC, 1982 (Box 1058, Folder 7)
    - Training: general, 1970-88, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 8)
    - Constituent Groups
      - Employed Women
        - Job Corps-YWCA Extension Residence Program
          - General, 1973 (Box 1058, Folder 9)
          - Courses in Beauty Culture, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 10)
        - New Jobs for Women, Philadelphia YWCA, 1970s (Box 1058, Folder 11)
      - Teen Age and Younger Girls
        - General (Box 1058, Folder 12)
        - Conferences, 1970s, n.d. (Box 1058, Folder 13)
      - Young Adults
        - Eastern Region Young Adult Conference, 1957 (Box 1058, Folder 14)
        - Young Women Committed to Action Assembly, 1978 (Box 1058, Folder 15)
    - Subjects
      - Camping and Outdoor Recreation: National Youth Conference on Conservation and Natural Beauty, Jun 1966 (Box 1059, Folder 1)
      - Health
        - General (Box 1059, Folder 2)
        - Food Nutrition and Safety, Pittsburgh YWCA, 1974-75 (Box 1059, Folder 3)
        - ENCOREplus Slide Presentation: script and slides, 1995 (Box 1059, Folder 4)
      - Recreation (Box 1059, Folder 5)
      - Religion: Mission of the YWCA: script and slides, 1977 (Box 1059, Folder 6)
      - Sports (Box 1059, Folder 7)
  - Subseries F. Student Work
    - General, n.d. (Box 1059, Folder 8-10)
    - Conferences and Council
      - General, 1951, n.d. (Box 1059, Folder 11)
      - Lake Geneva Conference: script and slides, 1957 (Box 1059, Folder 12)
      - National Student Council, Coe College, 1978 (Box 1059, Folder 13)
    - "Albuquerque Project": script and slides for recruitment, 1965 (Box 1059, Folder 14)
    - Washington Student Citizenship Seminar, 1950 (Box 1059, Folder 15)
  - Subseries G. Community Associations
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1060, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified (Box 1060, Folder 2)
    - California (Box 1060, Folder 3)
    - Connecticut (Box 1060, Folder 4)
    - Florida (Box 1060, Folder 5)
    - Illinois (Box 1060, Folder 6)
    - Indiana (Box 1060, Folder 7)
    - Montana (Box 1060, Folder 8)
    - New Jersey: Maple Run Area Migrant Projects, summer 1964 (Box 1060, Folder 9)
    - New York: White Plains (Box 1060, Folder 10)
    - North Carolina (Box 1060, Folder 11)
    - Ohio (Box 1060, Folder 12)
    - Pennsylvania (Box 1060, Folder 13)
    - Puerto Rico (Box 1060, Folder 14)
    - Virginia (Box 1060, Folder 15)
    - Washington (Box 1060, Folder 16)
- Film strips, 3
  Scope and Content
  This Series contains scripts for 3 filmstrips for which no strip survives and one filmstrip late 1940s-mid 1950s.
  - Scripts [no surviving filmstrip]
    - "Around the World with the YWCA," 1949 (Box 1061, Folder 1)
    - National Support filmstrip, 1959 (Box 1061, Folder 2)
    - "The Story of Miss 'Y' and the YWCA Retirement Fund," 1965 (Box 1061, Folder 3)
  - Filmstrip: "The House that Y Built," circa 1957 (Box 1061, Folder 4)